<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='RFC1583'>

<front>
<title>OSPF Version 2</title>
<author initials='J.' surname='Moy' fullname='John Moy'>
<organization>Proteon, Inc.</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>9 Technology Drive</street>
<city>Westborough</city>
<region>MA</region>
<code>01581</code>
<country>US</country></postal>
<phone>+1 508 898 2800</phone>
<facsimile>+1 508 898 3176</facsimile>
<email>jmoy@proteon.com</email></address></author>
<date year='1994' month='March' />
<abstract>
<t>This memo documents version 2 of the OSPF protocol.  OSPF is a link-state routing protocol.  It is designed to be run internal to a single Autonomous System.  Each OSPF router maintains an identical database describing the Autonomous System's topology.  From this database, a routing table is calculated by constructing a shortest- path tree.</t>
<t>OSPF recalculates routes quickly in the face of topological changes, utilizing a minimum of routing protocol traffic.  OSPF provides support for equal-cost multipath.  Separate routes can be calculated for each IP Type of Service.  An area routing capability is provided, enabling an additional level of routing protection and a reduction in routing protocol traffic.  In addition, all OSPF routing protocol exchanges are authenticated.</t>
<t>OSPF Version 2 was originally documented in RFC 1247. The differences between RFC 1247 and this memo are explained in Appendix E. The differences consist of bug fixes and clarifications, and are backward-compatible in nature. Implementations of RFC 1247 and of this memo will interoperate.</t>
<t>Please send comments to ospf@gated.cornell.edu.</t></abstract></front>

<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='1583' />
<format type='TXT' octets='532636' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc1583.txt' />
<format type='PS' octets='990794' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc1583.ps' />
<format type='PDF' octets='465711' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc1583.pdf' />
</reference>
