<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='RFC0826'>

<front>
<title>Ethernet Address Resolution Protocol: Or converting network protocol addresses to 48.bit Ethernet address for transmission on Ethernet hardware</title>
<author initials='D.' surname='Plummer' fullname='David C. Plummer'>
<organization>Symbolics, Inc.</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>243 Vassar Street</street>
<city>Cambridge</city>
<region>MA</region>
<code>02139</code>
<country>US</country></postal>
<email>DCP@MIT-MC</email></address></author>
<date year='1982' day='1' month='November' />
<abstract>
<t>The implementation of protocol P on a sending host S decides, through protocol P's routing mechanism, that it wants to transmit to a target host T located some place on a connected piece of 10Mbit Ethernet cable.  To actually transmit the Ethernet packet a 48.bit Ethernet address must be generated.  The addresses of hosts within protocol P are not always compatible with the corresponding Ethernet address (being different lengths or values).  Presented here is a protocol that allows dynamic distribution of the information needed to build tables to translate an address A in protocol P's address space into a 48.bit Ethernet address.</t>
<t>Generalizations have been made which allow the protocol to be used for non-10Mbit Ethernet hardware.  Some packet radio networks are examples of such hardware.</t>
<t>The protocol proposed here is the result of a great deal of discussion with several other people, most notably J. Noel Chiappa, Yogen Dalal, and James E. Kulp, and helpful comments from David Moon.</t>
<t>The purpose of this RFC is to present a method of Converting Protocol Addresses (e.g., IP addresses) to Local Network Addresses (e.g., Ethernet addresses).  This is a issue of general concern in the ARPA Internet community at this time.  The method proposed here is presented for your consideration and comment.  This is not the specification of a Internet Standard.</t></abstract></front>

<seriesInfo name='STD' value='37' />
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='826' />
<format type='TXT' octets='22026' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc826.txt' />
</reference>
