<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='RFC2445'>

<front>
<title abbrev='iCalendar'>Internet Calendaring and Scheduling Core Object Specification (iCalendar)</title>
<author initials='F.' surname='Dawson' fullname='Frank Dawson'>
<organization>Lotus Development Corporation</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>6544 Battleford Drive</street>
<city>Raleigh</city>
<region>NC</region>
<code>27613-3502</code>
<country>USA</country></postal>
<phone>+1-919-676-9515</phone>
<facsimile>+1-919-676-9564</facsimile>
<email>Frank_Dawson@Lotus.com</email>
<uri>http://home.earthlink.net/~fdawson</uri></address></author>
<author initials='D.' surname='Stenerson' fullname='Derik Stenerson'>
<organization>Microsoft Corporation</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>One Microsoft Way</street>
<city>Redmond</city>
<region>WA</region>
<code>98052-6399</code>
<country>USA</country></postal>
<phone>+1-425-936-5522</phone>
<facsimile>+1-425-936-7329</facsimile>
<email>deriks@Microsoft.com</email></address></author>
<author>
<organization /></author>
<author>
<organization /></author>
<date year='1998' month='November' />
<area>Applications</area>
<keyword>calendaring</keyword>
<keyword>scheduling</keyword>
<keyword>PIM</keyword>
<abstract>
<t>
   There is a clear need to provide and deploy interoperable calendaring
   and scheduling services for the Internet. Current group scheduling
   and Personal Information Management (PIM) products are being extended
   for use across the Internet, today, in proprietary ways. This memo
   has been defined to provide the definition of a common format for
   openly exchanging calendaring and scheduling information across the
   Internet.
</t>
<t>
   This memo is formatted as a registration for a MIME media type per
   . However, the format in this memo is equally applicable
   for use outside of a MIME message content type.
</t>
<t>
   The proposed media type value is &apos;text/calendar&apos;. This string would
   label a media type containing calendaring and scheduling information
   encoded as text characters formatted in a manner outlined below.
</t>
<t>
   This MIME media type provides a standard content type for capturing
   calendar event, to-do and journal entry information. It also can be
   used to convey free/busy time information. The content type is
   suitable as a MIME message entity that can be transferred over MIME
   based email systems, using HTTP or some other Internet transport. In
   addition, the content type is useful as an object for interactions
   between desktop applications using the operating system clipboard,
   drag/drop or file systems capabilities.
</t>
<t>
   This memo is based on the earlier work of the vCalendar specification
   for the exchange of personal calendaring and scheduling information.
   In order to avoid confusion with this referenced work, this memo is
   to be known as the iCalendar specification.
</t>
<t>
   This memo defines the format for specifying iCalendar object methods.
   An iCalendar object method is a set of usage constraints for the
   iCalendar object. For example, these methods might define scheduling
   messages that request an event be scheduled, reply to an event
   request, send a cancellation notice for an event, modify or replace
   the definition of an event, provide a counter proposal for an
   original event request, delegate an event request to another
   individual, request free or busy time, reply to a free or busy time
   request, or provide similar scheduling messages for a to-do or
   journal entry calendar component. The iCalendar Transport-indendent
   Interoperability Protocol (iTIP) defined in  is one such
   scheduling protocol.
</t></abstract></front>

<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='2445' />
<format type='TXT' octets='291838' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc2445.txt' />
<format type='XML' octets='305617' target='http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/xml/rfc2445.xml' />
</reference>
