<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='RFC1530'>

<front>
<title abbrev='General Principles and Policy'>Principles of Operation for the TPC.INT Subdomain: General Principles and Policy</title>
<author initials='C.' surname='Malamud' fullname='Carl Malamud'>
<organization>Internet Multicasting Service</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>The National Press Building</street>
<street>Suite 1155</street>
<city>Washington</city>
<region>DC</region>
<code>20045</code>
<country>US</country></postal>
<phone>+1 202 628 2044</phone>
<facsimile>+1 202 628 2042</facsimile>
<email>carl@malamud.com</email></address></author>
<author initials='M.' surname='Rose' fullname='Marshall T. Rose'>
<organization>Dover Beach Consulting, Inc.</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>420 Whisman Court</street>
<city>Mountain View</city>
<region>CA</region>
<code>94043-2186</code>
<country>US</country></postal>
<phone>+1 415 968 1052</phone>
<facsimile>+1 415 968 2510</facsimile>
<email>mrose@dbc.mtview.ca.us</email></address></author>
<date year='1993' month='October' />
<abstract>
<t>This document defines the initial principles of operation for the tpc.int subdomain, a collection of service listings accessible over the Internet infrastructure through an administered namespace contained within the Domain Name System,.</t>
<t>This document is informational and applies only to those Internet sites that choose to register themselves within the tpc.int subdomain.  The tpc.int subdomain is organized as a cooperative of the sites that provide access within the context of the subdomain. Policy for the subdomain is set by a board responsible to the cooperative.</t>
<t>The primary purpose of the tpc.int subdomain is to provide transparent mapping between general-purpose computers on the Internet and special-purpose devices directly connected to the telephone network.  Initially, a remote printing service is defined,which ties together G3-compatible facsimile devices on the telephone network with users of electronic mail in the Internet and associated message-handling domains connected to the Internet by application-layer gateways.</t>
<t>It should be noted that remote printer gateways have long been technically feasible and have become an integral part of many individual networks.  The tpc.int subdomain integrates individual sites into a common namespace, transforming remote printing from a single-site, value-added service into an integral transparent service in the global Internet.</t></abstract></front>

<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='1530' />
<format type='TXT' octets='15031' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc1530.txt' />
</reference>
