<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='RFC2170'>

<front>
<title abbrev='AREQUIPA'>Application REQuested IP over ATM (AREQUIPA)</title>
<author initials='W.' surname='Almesberger' fullname='Werner Almesberger'>
<organization>Jean-Yves Le Boudec,</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>Philippe Oechslin (contact author)</street></postal>
<email>{almesber,</email></address></author>
<date year='1997' month='July' />
<area>Internet</area>
<keyword>asynchronous transfer mode</keyword>
<abstract>
<t>
   This RFC has not had the benefit of the rigorous peer review that is
   part of the process in an IETF working group.  The technology it
   describes has been implemented and is now undergoing testing. It
   would be wise to analyze the results of this testing as well as to
   understand alternatives before committing to this approach for IP
   over ATM with QoS guarantees.
</t>
<t>
   This document specifies a method for allowing ATM-attached hosts that
   have direct ATM connectivity to set up end-to-end IP over ATM
   connections within the reachable ATM cloud, on request from
   applications, and for the exclusive use by the requesting
   applications. This allows the requesting applications to benefit in a
   straightforward way from ATM&apos;s inherent ability to guarantee the
   quality of service (QoS).
</t>
<t>
   Given a mapping from service classes, as defined by INTSERV, to
   ATM traffic descriptors, Arequipa can be used to implement integrated
   services over ATM link layers. Usage of Arequipa to provide
   integrated services even if ATM is only available for intermediate
   links is not discussed in this document but should be straight-
   forward.
</t>
<t>
   The major advantage of using an approach like Arequipa is that it
   needs to be implemented only on the hosts using it. It requires no
   extra service (eg. NHRP or RSVP) to be deployed on the switches or
   routers of the ATM cloud.
   We discuss the implementation of Arequipa for hosts running IPv4 and
   IPv6. As an illustration, we also discuss how World-Wide-Web
   applications can use Arequipa to deliver documents with a guaranteed
   quality of service.
</t>
<t>
   In particular we show how

<list>
<t>
     - Arequipa can be implemented in IPv4 by slightly modifying the
</t>
<t>
     - Arequipa can be implemented in IPv6 by the appropriate use of
       flow labels and the extension of the neighbour cache,
</t>
<t>
     - Arequipa can be used in the Web by adding extra information in
       the headers of HTTP requests and responses.
</t></list></t>
<t>
   Finally, we address safety and security implications.
</t></abstract>
<note title='IESG Note'>
<t>
   This RFC has not had the benefit of the rigorous peer review that is
   part of the process in an IETF working group.  The technology it
   describes has been implemented and is now undergoing testing. It
   would be wise to analyze the results of this testing as well as to
   understand alternatives before committing to this approach for IP
   over ATM with QoS guarantees.
</t></note></front>

<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='2170' />
<format type='TXT' octets='22874' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc2170.txt' />
<format type='XML' octets='25467' target='http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/xml/rfc2170.xml' />
</reference>
