<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='RFC2107'>

<front>
<title abbrev='ATMP'>Ascend Tunnel Management Protocol - ATMP</title>
<author initials='K.' surname='Hamzeh' fullname='Kory Hamzeh'>
<organization>Ascend Communications</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>1275 Harbor Bay Parkway</street>
<street>Alameda</street>
<street>CA 94502</street></postal>
<email>kory@ascend.com</email></address></author>
<date year='1997' month='February' />
<area>Routing</area>
<keyword>tunnel</keyword>
<keyword>dial-in</keyword>
<abstract>
<t>
   This note documents a private protocol for tunnel management.  This
   protocol is NOT the product of an IETF working group nor is it a
   standards track document. There is ongoing effort in an IETF working
   group which could result in a standards track document which
   specifies a protocol which provides similar functionality.
</t>
<t>
   This document specifies a generic tunnel management protocol that
   allows remote dial-in users to access their home network as if they
   were directly attached to the home network.  The user&apos;s client
   software uses an address contained in the home network address space
   for the remote access.  Packets to and from the home network are
   tunneled by the Network Access Server (NAS) to which the user
   connects and a Home Agent (HA) on the user&apos;s home network.  This
   allows for the support of access to Virtual Private Networks and also
   allows for the use of protocols other than IP to be carried over the
   tunnel.  An example of how the RADIUS (Remote Authentication Dial In
   User Service) can be used to provide the necessary configuration
   information to support this service is also provided.
</t></abstract>
<note title='IESG Note'>
<t>
   This note documents a private protocol for tunnel management.  This
   protocol is NOT the product of an IETF working group nor is it a
   standards track document. There is ongoing effort in an IETF working
   group which could result in a standards track document which
   specifies a protocol which provides similar functionality.
</t></note></front>

<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='2107' />
<format type='TXT' octets='44300' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc2107.txt' />
<format type='XML' octets='47784' target='http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/xml/rfc2107.xml' />
</reference>
