<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='RFC2298'>

<front>
<title abbrev='Message Disposition Notifications'>An Extensible Message Format for Message Disposition Notifications</title>
<author initials='R.' surname='Fajman' fullname='Roger Fajman'>
<organization>National Institutes of Health</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>Building 12A</street>
<street>Room 3063</street>
<street>12 South Drive MSC 5659</street>
<street>Bethesda</street>
<street>Maryland 20892-5659</street>
<country>USA</country></postal>
<phone>+1 301 402 4265</phone>
<facsimile>+1 301 480 6241</facsimile>
<email>raf@cu.nih.gov</email></address></author>
<date year='1998' month='March' />
<area>Applications</area>
<keyword>ITU message handling service protocol</keyword>
<keyword>content-type</keyword>
<keyword>multipurpose internet mail extensions</keyword>
<abstract>
<t>
   This memo defines a MIME content-type that may be used by a mail user
   agent (UA) or electronic mail gateway to report the disposition of a
   message after it has been sucessfully delivered to a recipient.  This
   content-type is intended to be machine-processable.  Additional
   message headers are also defined to permit Message Disposition
   Notifications (MDNs) to be requested by the sender of a message.  The
   purpose is to extend Internet Mail to support functionality often
   found in other messaging systems, such as X.400 and the proprietary
   &quot;LAN-based&quot; systems, and often referred to as &quot;read receipts,&quot;
   &quot;acknowledgements,&quot; or &quot;receipt notifications.&quot;  The intention is to
   do this while respecting the privacy concerns that have often been
   expressed when such functions have been discussed in the past.
</t>
<t>
   Because many messages are sent between the Internet and other
   messaging systems (such as X.400 or the proprietary &quot;LAN-based&quot;
   systems), the MDN protocol is designed to be useful in a multi-
   protocol messaging environment.  To this end, the protocol described
   in this memo provides for the carriage of &quot;foreign&quot; addresses, in
   addition to those normally used in Internet Mail.  Additional
   attributes may also be defined to support &quot;tunneling&quot; of foreign
   notifications through Internet Mail.
</t></abstract></front>

<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='2298' />
<format type='TXT' octets='62059' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc2298.txt' />
<format type='XML' octets='66306' target='http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/xml/rfc2298.xml' />
</reference>
