<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='RFC2589'>

<front>
<title abbrev='LDAPv3 Extensions for Dynamic Directory Services'>Lightweight Directory Access Protocol (v3): Extensions for Dynamic Directory Services</title>
<author initials='Y.' surname='Yaacovi' fullname='Yoram Yaacovi'>
<organization>Microsoft</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>One Microsoft way</street>
<city>Redmond</city>
<region>WA</region>
<code>98052</code>
<country>US</country></postal>
<phone>+1 206 936 9629</phone>
<email>yoramy@microsoft.com</email></address></author>
<author initials='M.' surname='Wahl' fullname='Mark Wahl'>
<organization>Innosoft International, Inc.</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>8911 Capital of Texas Highway</street>
<street>Suite 4140</street>
<city>Austin</city>
<region>TX</region>
<code>78759</code>
<country>US</country></postal>
<email>M.Wahl@innosoft.com</email></address></author>
<author initials='T.' surname='Genovese' fullname='Tony Genovese'>
<organization>Microsoft</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>One Microsoft way</street>
<city>Redmond</city>
<region>WA</region>
<code>98052</code>
<country>US</country></postal>
<phone>+1 206 703 0852</phone>
<email>tonyg@microsoft.com</email></address></author>
<date year='1999' month='May' />
<abstract>
<t>This document defines the requirements for dynamic
directory services 
and specifies the format of request and response extended operations
for supporting client-server interoperation in a dynamic directories
environment.</t>
<t>TheLightweight Directory Access Protocol (LDAP)supports
lightweight access to static directory services, allowing relatively
fast search and update access.
Static directory services store
information about people that persists in its accuracy and value over
a long period of time.</t>
<t>Dynamic directory services are different in that they store
information that only persists in its accuracy and value when it is
being periodically refreshed.
This information is stored as dynamic
entries in the directory.
A typical use will be a client or a person
that is either online - in which case it has an entry in the
directory, or is offline - in which case its entry disappears from
the directory.
Though the protocol operations and attributes used by
dynamic directory services are similar to the ones used for static
directory services, clients that store dynamic information in the
directory need to periodically refresh this information, in order to
prevent it from disappearing.
If dynamic entries are not refreshed
within a given timeout, they will be removed from the directory.
For
example, this will happen if the client that set them goes offline.</t>
<t>A flow control mechanism from the server is also described that
allows a server to inform clients how often they should refresh their
presence.</t></abstract></front>

<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='2589' />
<format type='TXT' octets='26855' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc2589.txt' />
</reference>
