<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='RFC2479'>

<front>
<title abbrev='IDUP-GSS-API'>Independent Data Unit Protection Generic Security Service Application Program Interface (IDUP-GSS-API)</title>
<author initials='C.' surname='Adams' fullname='Carlisle Adams'>
<organization>Entrust Technologies</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>750 Heron Road</street>
<street>Suite E08</street>
<city>Ottawa</city>
<region>Ontario</region>
<code>K1V 1A7</code>
<country>CANADA</country></postal>
<phone>+1 613 247 3180</phone>
<email>cadams@entrust.com</email></address></author>
<date year='1998' month='December' />
<area>Security</area>
<keyword>application program interface</keyword>
<keyword>generic security service</keyword>
<keyword>independent data unit protection</keyword>
<keyword>security</keyword>
<abstract>
<t>
   The IDUP-GSS-API extends the GSS-API  for applications
   requiring protection of a generic data unit (such as a file or
   message) in a way which is independent of the protection of any other
   data unit and independent of any concurrent contact with designated
   &quot;receivers&quot; of the data unit.  Thus, it is suitable for applications
   such as secure electronic mail where data needs to be protected
   without any on-line connection with the intended recipient(s) of that
   data.  The protection offered by IDUP includes services such as data
   origin authentication with data integrity, data confidentiality with
   data integrity, and support for non-repudiation services.  Subsequent
   to being protected, the data unit can be transferred to the
   recipient(s) - or to an archive - perhaps to be processed
   (&quot;unprotected&quot;) only days or years later.
</t>
<t>
   Throughout the remainder of this document, the &quot;unit&quot; of data
   described in the above paragraph will be referred to as an IDU
   (Independent Data Unit).  The IDU can be of any size (the application
   may, if it wishes, split the IDU into pieces and have the protection
   computed a piece at a time, but the resulting protection token
   applies to the entire IDU).  However, the primary characteristic of
   an IDU is that it represents a stand-alone unit of data whose
   protection is entirely independent of any other unit of data.  If an
   application protects several IDUs and sends them all to a single
   receiver, the IDUs may be unprotected by that receiver in any order
   over any time span; no logical connection of any kind is implied by
   the protection process itself.
</t>
<t>
   As with RFC-2078, this IDUP-GSS-API definition provides security
   services to callers in a generic fashion, supportable with a range of
   underlying mechanisms and technologies and hence allowing source-
   level portability of applications to different environments. This
   specification defines IDUP-GSS-API services and primitives at a level
   independent of underlying mechanism and programming language
   environment, and is to be complemented by other, related
   specifications:

<list>
<t>
      - documents defining specific parameter bindings for particular
        language environments;
      - documents defining token formats, protocols, and procedures to
        be implemented in order to realize IDUP-GSS-API services atop
        particular security mechanisms.
</t></list></t></abstract></front>

<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='2479' />
<format type='TXT' octets='156070' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc2479.txt' />
<format type='HTML' octets='190988' target='http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/html/rfc2479.html' />
<format type='XML' octets='157270' target='http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/xml/rfc2479.xml' />
</reference>
