<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='RFC1341'>

<front>
<title abbrev='MIME: Multipurpose Internet Mail Extensions'>MIME (Multipurpose Internet Mail Extensions): Mechanisms for Specifying and Describing the Format of Internet Message Bodies</title>
<author initials='N.' surname='Borenstein' fullname='Nathaniel S. Borenstein'>
<organization>Bellcore</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>445 South St.</street>
<street>MRE 2D-296</street>
<city>Morristown</city>
<region>NJ</region>
<code>07962-1910</code>
<country>US</country></postal>
<phone>+1 201 829 4270</phone>
<facsimile>+1 201 829 7019</facsimile>
<email>nsb@bellcore.com</email></address></author>
<author initials='N.' surname='Freed' fullname='Ned Freed'>
<organization>Innosoft International, Inc.</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>250 West First Street</street>
<street>Suite 240</street>
<city>Claremont</city>
<region>CA</region>
<code>91711</code>
<country>US</country></postal>
<phone>+1 714 624 7907</phone>
<facsimile>+1 714 621 5319</facsimile>
<email>ned@innosoft.com</email></address></author>
<date year='1992' month='June' />
<abstract>
<t>RFC 822 defines  a  message  representation  protocol  which specifies  considerable  detail  about  message headers, but which leaves the message content, or message body,  as  flat ASCII  text.   This document redefines the format of message bodies to allow multi-part textual and  non-textual  message bodies  to  be  represented  and  exchanged  without loss of information.   This is based on earlier work  documented  in RFC  934  and  RFC  1049, but extends and revises that work. Because RFC 822 said so little about  message  bodies,  this document  is  largely  orthogonal to (rather than a revision of) RFC 822.</t>
<t>In  particular,  this  document  is  designed to provide facilities  to include multiple objects in a single message, to represent body text in  character  sets  other  than  US- ASCII,  to  represent formatted multi-font text messages, to represent non-textual material  such  as  images  and  audio fragments,  and  generally  to  facilitate  later extensions defining new types of Internet mail for use  by  cooperating mail agents.</t>
<t>This document does NOT extend Internet mail header fields to permit  anything  other  than  US-ASCII  text  data.   It is recognized that such extensions are necessary, and they  are the subject of a companion document.</t>
<t>A table of contents appears at the end of this document.</t></abstract></front>

<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='1341' />
<format type='TXT' octets='211117' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc1341.txt' />
<format type='PS' octets='347082' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc1341.ps' />
<format type='PDF' octets='192244' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc1341.pdf' />
</reference>
