<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='RFC2120'>

<front>
<title abbrev='X.500 Root Naming'>Managing the X.500 Root Naming Context</title>
<author initials='D.W.' surname='Chadwick' fullname='D W Chadwick'>
<organization>IT Institute</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>University of Salford</street>
<street>Salford</street>
<street>M5 4WT</street>
<street>England</street></postal>
<phone>+44 161 745 5351</phone>
<facsimile>+44 161 745 8169</facsimile>
<email>D.W.Chadwick@iti.salford.ac.uk</email></address></author>
<date year='1997' month='March' />
<area>Applications</area>
<keyword>X.500</keyword>
<keyword>ITU abstract syntax notation one</keyword>
<keyword>ITU directory service protocol</keyword>
<abstract>
<t>
   The X.500 Standard  has the concept of first level DSAs,
   whose administrators must collectively manage the root naming context
   through bi-lateral agreements or other private means which are
   outside the scope of the X.500 Standard.
</t>
<t>
   The NameFLOW-Paradise X.500 service has an established procedure for
   managing the root naming context, which currently uses Quipu
   proprietary replication mechanisms and a root DSA. The benefits that
   derive from this are twofold:

<list>
<t>
      - firstly it is much easier to co-ordinate the management of the
      root context information, when there is a central point of
      administration,
</t>
<t>
      - secondly the performance of one-level Search operations is
      greatly improved because the Quipu distribution and replication
      mechanism does not have a restriction that exists in the 1988 and
      1993 X.500 Standard.
</t></list></t>
<t>
   The NameFLOW-Paradise project is moving towards 1993 ISO X.500
   Standard replication protocols and wants to standardise the protocol
   and procedure for managing the root naming context which will be
   based on 1993 X.500 Standard protocols. Such a protocol and procedure
   will be useful to private X.500 domains as well as to the Internet
   X.500 public domain. It is imperative that overall system performance
   is not degraded by this transition.
</t>
<t>
   This document describes the use of 1993 ISO X.500 Standard protocols
   for managing the root context. Whilst the ASN.1 is compatible with
   that of the X.500 Standard, the actual settings of the parameters are
   supplementary to that of the X.500 Standard.
</t></abstract></front>

<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='2120' />
<format type='TXT' octets='30773' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc2120.txt' />
<format type='HTML' octets='40285' target='http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/html/rfc2120.html' />
<format type='XML' octets='23965' target='http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/xml/rfc2120.xml' />
</reference>
