<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='RFC2191'>

<front>
<title abbrev='VENUS'>VENUS - Very Extensive Non-Unicast Service</title>
<author initials='G.' surname='Armitage' fullname='Grenville Armitage'>
<organization>Bell Labs, Lucent Technologies.</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>101 Crawfords Corner Rd</street>
<street>Holmdel</street>
<street>NJ</street>
<street>07733</street>
<country>USA</country></postal>
<email>gja@dnrc.bell-labs.com</email></address></author>
<date year='1997' month='September' />
<area>Internet</area>
<keyword>ATM</keyword>
<keyword>MARS</keyword>
<abstract>
<t>
   The MARS model (RFC2022) provides a solution to intra-LIS IP
   multicasting over ATM, establishing and managing the use of ATM pt-
   mpt SVCs for IP multicast packet forwarding. Inter-LIS multicast
   forwarding is achieved using Mrouters, in a similar manner to which
   the &quot;Classical IP over ATM&quot; model uses Routers to inter-connect LISes
   for unicast traffic. The development of unicast IP shortcut
   mechanisms (e.g.  NHRP) has led some people to request the
   development of a Multicast equivalent. There are a number of
   different approaches. This document focuses exclusively on the
   problems associated with extending the MARS model to cover multiple
   clusters or clusters spanning more than one subnet. It describes a
   hypothetical solution, dubbed &quot;Very Extensive NonUnicast Service&quot;
   (VENUS), and shows how complex such a service would be. It is also
   noted that VENUS ultimately has the look and feel of a single, large
   cluster using a distributed MARS.  This document is being issued to
   help focus ION efforts towards alternative solutions for establishing
   ATM level multicast connections between LISes.
</t></abstract></front>

<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='2191' />
<format type='TXT' octets='31316' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc2191.txt' />
<format type='XML' octets='33858' target='http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/xml/rfc2191.xml' />
</reference>
