<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='RFC2047'>

<front>
<title abbrev='Message Header Extensions'>MIME (Multipurpose Internet Mail Extensions) Part Three: Message Header Extensions for Non-ASCII Text</title>
<author initials='K.' surname='Moore' fullname='Keith Moore'>
<organization>University of Tennessee</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>107 Ayres Hall</street>
<street>Knoxville TN 37996-1301</street></postal>
<email>moore@cs.utk.edu</email></address></author>
<date year='1996' month='November' />
<area>Applications</area>
<keyword>Amercian Standard Code for Information Interchange</keyword>
<keyword>mail</keyword>
<keyword>multipurpose internet mail extensions</keyword>
<abstract>
<t>
   STD 11, RFC 822, defines a message representation protocol specifying
   considerable detail about US-ASCII message headers, and leaves the
   message content, or message body, as flat US-ASCII text.  This set of
   documents, collectively called the Multipurpose Internet Mail
   Extensions, or MIME, redefines the format of messages to allow for

<list>
<t>
   (1) textual message bodies in character sets other than US-ASCII,
</t>
<t>
   (2) an extensible set of different formats for non-textual message
       bodies,
</t>
<t>
   (3) multi-part message bodies, and
</t>
<t>
   (4) textual header information in character sets other than US-ASCII.
</t></list></t>
<t>
   These documents are based on earlier work documented in RFC 934, STD
   11, and RFC 1049, but extends and revises them.  Because RFC 822 said
   so little about message bodies, these documents are largely
   orthogonal to (rather than a revision of) RFC 822.
</t>
<t>
   This particular document is the third document in the series.  It
   describes extensions to RFC 822 to allow non-US-ASCII text data in
   Internet mail header fields.
   Other documents in this series include:

<list>
<t>
   + RFC 2045, which specifies the various headers used to describe
     the structure of MIME messages.
</t>
<t>
   + RFC 2046, which defines the general structure of the MIME media
     typing system and defines an initial set of media types,
</t>
<t>
   + RFC 2048, which specifies various IANA registration procedures
     for MIME-related facilities, and
</t>
<t>
   + RFC 2049, which describes MIME conformance criteria and
     provides some illustrative examples of MIME message formats,
     acknowledgements, and the bibliography.
</t></list></t>
<t>
   These documents are revisions of RFCs 1521, 1522, and 1590, which
   themselves were revisions of RFCs 1341 and 1342.  An appendix in RFC
   2049 describes differences and changes from previous versions.
</t></abstract></front>

<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='2047' />
<format type='TXT' octets='33262' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc2047.txt' />
<format type='XML' octets='39330' target='http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/xml/rfc2047.xml' />
</reference>
