<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='RFC2774'>

<front>
<title>An HTTP Extension Framework</title>
<author initials='H.' surname='Nielsen' fullname='Henrik Frystyk Nielsen'>
<organization abbrev='Microsoft'>Microsoft Corporation</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>1 Microsoft Way</street>
<city>Redmond</city>
<region>WA</region>
<code>98052</code>
<country>USA</country></postal>
<email>frystyk@microsoft.com</email></address></author>
<author initials='P.' surname='Leach' fullname='Paul J. Leach'>
<organization abbrev='Microsoft'>Microsoft Corporation</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>1 Microsoft Way</street>
<city>Redmond</city>
<region>WA</region>
<code>98052</code>
<country>USA</country></postal>
<email>paulle@microsoft.com</email></address></author>
<author initials='S.' surname='Lawrence' fullname='Scott Lawrence'>
<organization abbrev='Agranat Systems'>Agranat Systems, Inc.</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>5 Clocktower Place, Suite 400</street>
<city>Maynard</city>
<region>MA</region>
<code>01754</code>
<country>USA</country></postal>
<email>lawrence@agranat.com</email></address></author>
<date year='2000' month='February' />
<abstract>
<t>
     A wide range of applications have proposed various extensions of the
     HTTP protocol. Current efforts span an enormous range, including
     distributed authoring, collaboration, printing, and remote procedure
     call mechanisms. These HTTP extensions are not coordinated, since
     there has been no standard framework for defining extensions and
     thus, separation of concerns. This document describes a generic
     extension mechanism for HTTP, which is designed to address the
     tension between private agreement and public specification and to
     accommodate extension of applications using HTTP clients, servers,
     and proxies.  The proposal associates each extension with a globally
     unique identifier, and uses HTTP header fields to carry the extension
     identifier and related information between the parties involved in
     the extended communication.
    </t></abstract>
<note title='IESG Note'>
<t>
     This document was originally requested for Proposed Standard status.
     However, due to mixed reviews during Last Call and within the HTTP
     working group, it is being published as an Experimental document.
     This is not necessarily an indication of technical flaws in the
     document; rather, there is a more general concern about whether this
     document actually represents community consensus regarding the
     evolution of HTTP.  Additional study and discussion are needed before
     this can be determined.
  </t>
<t>
     Note also that when HTTP is used as a substrate for other protocols,
     it may be necessary or appropriate to use other extension mechanisms
     in addition to, or instead of, those defined here.  This document
     should therefore not be taken as a blueprint for adding extensions to
     HTTP, but it defines mechanisms that might be useful in such
     circumstances.
  </t></note></front>

<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='2774' />
<format type='TXT' octets='39719' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc2774.txt' />
<format type='HTML' octets='68550' target='http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/html/rfc2774.html' />
<format type='XML' octets='52987' target='http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/xml/rfc2774.xml' />
</reference>
