<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='RFC2408'>

<front>
<title abbrev='ISAKMP'>Internet Security Association and Key Management Protocol (ISAKMP)</title>
<author initials='D.' surname='Maughan' fullname='Douglas Maughan'>
<organization>National Security Agency</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>ATTN: R23</street>
<street>9800 Savage Road</street>
<street>Ft.  Meade</street>
<street>MD. 20755-6000</street></postal>
<phone>301-688-0847</phone>
<email>wdm@tycho.ncsc.mil</email></address></author>
<author initials='M.' surname='Schneider' fullname='Mark Schneider'>
<organization>National Security Agency</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>ATTN: R23</street>
<street>9800 Savage Road</street>
<street>Ft.  Meade</street>
<street>MD. 20755-6000</street></postal>
<phone>301-688-0851</phone>
<email>mss@tycho.ncsc.mil</email></address></author>
<author initials='M.' surname='Schertler' fullname='Mark Schertler'>
<organization>Securify, Inc.</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>2415-B Charleston Road</street>
<street>Mountain View</street>
<street>CA 94043</street></postal>
<phone>410-715-9399</phone>
<uri>er@raba.com</uri></address></author>
<date year='1998' month='November' />
<area>Security</area>
<keyword>cryptographic</keyword>
<keyword>internet security association and key management protocol</keyword>
<keyword>key management</keyword>
<keyword>security</keyword>
<abstract>
<t>
   This memo describes a protocol utilizing security concepts necessary
   for establishing Security Associations (SA) and cryptographic keys in
   an Internet environment.  A Security Association protocol that
   negotiates, establishes, modifies and deletes Security Associations
   and their attributes is required for an evolving Internet, where
   there will be numerous security mechanisms and several options for
   each security mechanism.  The key management protocol must be robust
   in order to handle public key generation for the Internet community
   at large and private key requirements for those private networks with
   that requirement.  The Internet Security Association and Key
   Management Protocol (ISAKMP) defines the procedures for
   authenticating a communicating peer, creation and management of
   Security Associations, key generation techniques, and threat
   mitigation (e.g.  denial of service and replay attacks).  All of
   these are necessary to establish and maintain secure communications
   (via IP Security Service or any other security protocol) in an
   Internet environment.
</t></abstract></front>

<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='2408' />
<format type='TXT' octets='209175' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc2408.txt' />
<format type='XML' octets='202083' target='http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/xml/rfc2408.xml' />
</reference>
