<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='RFC2421'>

<front>
<title abbrev='VPIM v2'>Voice Profile for Internet Mail - version 2</title>
<author initials='G.M.' surname='Vaudreuil' fullname='Gregory M. Vaudreuil'>
<organization>Lucent Technologies, Octel Messaging Division</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>17080 Dallas Parkway</street>
<city>Dallas</city>
<region>TX</region>
<code>75248-1905</code>
<country>USA</country></postal>
<phone>+1 972 733 2722</phone>
<email>GregV@Lucent.Com</email></address></author>
<author initials='G.W.' surname='Parsons' fullname='Glenn W. Parsons'>
<organization>Northern Telecom</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>P.O. Box 3511</street>
<street>Station C</street>
<city>Ottawa</city>
<region>ON</region>
<code>K1Y 4H7</code>
<country>Canada</country></postal>
<phone>+1 613 763 7582</phone>
<facsimile>+1 613 763 4461</facsimile>
<email>Glenn.Parsons@Nortel.ca</email></address></author>
<date year='1998' month='September' />
<area>Applications</area>
<keyword>audio</keyword>
<keyword>mail</keyword>
<abstract>
<t>
   A class of special-purpose computers has evolved to provide voice
   messaging services.  These machines generally interface to a
   telephone switch and provide call answering and voice messaging
   services.  Traditionally, messages sent to a non-local machine are
   transported using analog networking protocols based on DTMF signaling
   and analog voice playback.  As the demand for networking increases,
   there is a need for a standard high-quality digital protocol to
   connect these machines.  The following document is a profile of the
   Internet standard MIME and ESMTP protocols for use as a digital voice
   messaging networking protocol. The profile is referred to as VPIM
   (Voice Profile for Internet Mail) in this document.
</t>
<t>
   This profile is based on earlier work in the Audio Message
   Interchange Specification (AMIS) group that defined a voice messaging
   protocol based on X.400 technology.  This profile is intended to
   satisfy the user requirements statement from that earlier work with
   the industry standard ESMTP/MIME mail protocol infrastructures
   already used within corporate intranets. This second version of VPIM
   is based on implementation experience and obsoletes RFC 1911 which
   describes version 1 of the profile.
</t></abstract>
<note title='Working Group Summary'>
<t>
   This profile is not the product of an IETF working group, though
   several have reviewed the document.  It is instead the product of the
   VPIM Work Group of the Electronic Messaging Association (EMA).  This
   work group, which has representatives from most major voice mail
   vendors and several email vendors, has held several interoperability
   demonstrations between voice messaging vendors and is currently
   promoting VPIM trials and deployment.
</t></note></front>

<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='2421' />
<format type='TXT' octets='123663' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc2421.txt' />
<format type='HTML' octets='190720' target='http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/html/rfc2421.html' />
<format type='XML' octets='183488' target='http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/xml/rfc2421.xml' />
</reference>
